m 211 -8 b 217 -6 217 -4 217 -2 l 217 24 b 217 26 217 29 211 31 l 31 31 b 26 29 26 26 26 24 l 26 -2 b 26 -4 26 -6 31 -8
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
m 200 -1 l 200 13 l 19 13 b 14 12 14 6 14 6 b 14 6 14 0 19 -1
m 38 -1 l 44 6 l 38 13 l 19 13 b 14 12 14 6 14 6 b 14 6 14 0 19 -1
翻译     牛奶器   嘟嘟矢
翻译     斑驳的小屋   木浅
翻译     蓑笠翁
校对     苏小黛
后期     8T
总监     somehacker
血   战      钢   锯   岭
+
根据真实故事改编
出自《圣经·以赛亚书》
你不曾听见吗
Have you not heard?
永在的神耶和华
The Lord is the everlasting God,
创造地极的主
the Creator of the ends of the Earth.
他不疲乏  也不困倦
He will not grow tired or weary,
他的智慧无法测度
and His understanding no one can fathom.
疲乏的  他赐能量
He gives strength to the weary
软弱的  他予气力
and increases the power of the weak.
便是少年人也会疲乏困倦
Even youths grow tired and weary,
强壮之人也必全然跌倒
and young men stumble and fall.
但那些等候耶和华之人  必重新得力
But those who hope in the Lord will renew their strength.
他们必如雄鹰展翅上腾
They will soar on wings like eagles.
他们奔跑却不困倦
They will run and not grow weary.
行走却不疲乏
They will walk and not be faint.
戴斯蒙德  坚持住
Desmond, hang on!
撑住  戴斯蒙德
Hang on, Desmond!
我们会带你离开这儿
We're going to get you out of here!
戴斯蒙德  戴斯蒙德
Desmond. Desmond!
蓝岭山脉  弗吉尼亚州
十六年前
干什么
What?
-等等我  -走快点
- Wait up. - Catch up.
等一下  告诉你一件事
Wait up, I've got something to tell you.
什么  哈尔
What, Hal?
比比谁先到山顶
Race you to the top.
你作弊
Hey! Cheater!
-山顶见  老头子  -喂
- See you later, slowpoke. - Hey!
-要拉你一把吗  -我能行
- Want a hand? - I got it.
-坐下吧  -你个笨蛋
- Sit down! - Ah, you dope!
-别闹了  -你别闹
- Quit it. - You quit it.
老天爷
For Pete's sake.
离山崖远一点儿  你们俩熊孩子
Hey! Get away from that ledge, you damn fool kids!
小心摔断脖子
You're going to break your necks!
是多斯家的孩子  跟他们老子一样疯
It's them Doss kids. Crazy as their old man.
他们挖通了杰克逊大道和主街...
They dug up the corner of Jackson and Main...
铺了一条人行道...
Putting in a sidewalk...
变化大到你们认不出来
You boys wouldn't recognize it now.
还有你  估计他们也记不得你了
Mind you, I doubt they'd recognize you.
连我都快被忘干净了
They hardly know me when I walk by 'em.
像跟你们一起阵亡了似的
It's like I died with you.
就好像咱们这帮人从没存在过
It's like we boys never existed.
今天就这么多了
Well, that's all I got for you today.
用右手挡住他  戴斯蒙德
Block him with your right, Desmond.
住手  听到没
Stop it! Do you hear me?
-他们为什么打架  -他俩打架有过理由吗
- What are they fighting about? - When'd they ever need a reason?
汤姆
Tom! Ugh!
拦着他们干什么  还省得我两个都得抽一顿
Why stop 'em? Saves me whipping them both.
这样我只需要揍打赢的那个就行了
This way, I just whip the one that wins.
汤姆
Tom!
不
No!
天哪
Oh, God.
汤姆  醒醒  能听见我说话吗
Tom! Wake up, can you hear me?
你他妈干了什么
What the hell have you done?
他失去意识了
He can't hear me.
我去拿冰块
I'll get some ice.
-把篮子拿开  -好的
- You shift that basket. - I got it.
他还有气吗
Is he breathing?
哈尔  哈尔  能听见吗
Hal? Hal, can you hear me?
哈尔  能听见我说话吗
Hal, can you hear me?
哈尔...醒醒
Hal... Come on.
他的瞳孔在放大
He's dilated.
《主祷文》
我们在天上的父
愿人都尊你的名为圣
愿你的国降临
愿你的旨意行在地上
如同行在天上
我们日用的饮食
今日赐给我们
免我们的债
如同我们免了人的债
不叫我们遇见试探
救我们脱离凶恶
因为国度 权柄 荣耀 全是你的
直到永远
阿门
第六诫
不可杀人
哈尔
Hal...
你以为你在干什么
What do you think you're doin'?
这下我得揍你了  你知道规矩的
I'm gonna have to beat you now, you know the rules.
听到没  戴斯蒙德
You hear me, Desmond?
-戴斯蒙德  -汤姆  住手
- Desmond! - Tom, stop.
现在打孩子有意义吗
What's that gonna teach the boy?
他已经够暴力了
He's violent enough already.
好吧  给他一个充满母爱的吻吧
Okay, fine, you go smother him in kisses.
告诉他这是个温柔祥和的世界
You tell him the world's a soft and gentle place.
哈尔会没事的
Hal's gonna be okay.
-我差点杀了他  -是的
- I could have killed him. - Yes, you could have.
杀人是最大的罪过
Murder, it's the worst sin of all.
取他人性命
And to take another man's life,
在主眼中是最深重的罪孽
that is the most egregious sin in the Lord's sight.
没有比这更伤他心的事了
Nothing hurts his heart so much.
听不懂人话是吗
Don't you understand English?
还要我再说一遍吗
Do I have to tell you again?
滚开  臭婆娘  不然打死你
You move, woman, or I will wallop you good and hard!
你们在吵什么  你还好吗  贝莎
What the hell's going on? You okay, Bertha?
管好你自己的事
You mind your own damned business!
睡一觉就好了  汤姆
Go sleep it off, Tom.
我恨他
I hate him.
妈妈
Momma?
他为什么这么恨我们
Why does he hate us so much?
他不是恨我们
Oh, he don't hate us.
有时他只是恨自己
He hates himself sometimes.
这不是你爸爸的本性
Your daddy tonight, that ain't the real him.
真希望你们像我一样知道他战前的样子
I wish you knew him like I did, before the war.
十五年后
赞美主
Praise the Lord
万民快乐欢欣
Let the people rejoice
请来
Oh, come
藉圣子耶稣来到父前
To the Father Through Jesus the Son
荣耀归主  他已成就大事功
And give him the glory great things He has done
我们唱得怎么样  戴斯蒙德
How'd we sound, Desmond?
像一群天使  妈
Like a heavenly host of angels, Mom.
你知道说谎是犯诫的  尤其在这里
Now, you know it's a sin to tell a lie, especially in this place.
我可没说是擅长唱歌的天使
Well, I ain't never said they were singing angels.
外面怎么了  戴斯蒙德
What's going on out there? Desmond!
抬起来  快抬起来
Get it up, get it up!
拽垫子把他拉出来
Drag him out. Just the tarp.
我叫辆救护车
I'll phone an ambulance.
不  来不及了  开约书亚的皮卡去
No, no time. Joshua's pickup.
-快去  -好的
- Quick! - Okay.
你会没事的  会没事的
You're going to be fine now. You're going to be fine.
林奇堡医院
医生会治好你
You're in good hands.
病人怎么了
What have we got here?
动脉破裂  拿针线来
It's a severed artery. Get some sutures.
好的医生
Yes, doctor.
压住伤口  是你绑的止血带吗
Put some pressure on it. Did you apply this tourniquet?
-是的  先生  -干得不错
- Yes, sir. - Nice work.
你可能救了这小伙子的命
You might have saved this boy's life.
能听见吗  你会没事的
You staying with us? You're going to be okay.
你叫什么  孩子
What's your name, son?
吉尔伯特
Gilbert.
-送手术室  -是的  准备手术
- Surgery? - Yeah, surgery.
振作点  你会没事的
Stay with us, you're gonna be okay.
疼吗
You feel pain?
振作点  好吗
Stay with us, okay?
参军体检在那边  这是献血室
Army physicals that way. This is for giving blood.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
不  这不是我的血  我没事
Oh, no, that's not mine. I'm fine.
谢谢关心  女士
Thank you for asking though, ma'am.
有什么需要吗
What do you need?
我的皮带
My belt.
我用来给受伤那个小伙子止血了
I lent it to the boy who had the accident.
没有它裤子可系不牢
My pants don't hold up so good without it.
它也不在我手里
Well, uh, I don't have your belt.
我知道  女士  在那边呢
No, I know that, ma'am. It's out there.
还绑在那小伙子腿上呢
It's right out there with the boy still.
好吧  我只负责采血
Okay. I'm just here to take blood.
那我献血
I'll give mine.
好吧  去那屋等着
Okay, go to that room over there and wait with the others.
到时候会叫你的
I'll call you.
那个屋
That room.
之前献过血吗  这位...
You ever given blood before, Mr...
我姓多斯
Doss.
但朋友们都叫我戴斯蒙德
But my friends call me Desmond.
没献过  女士  这是第一次
No, ma'am, this is my first time.
我做梦都想当个医生
I always dreamed about being a doctor.
不过  我没念过多少书
But, uh, I didn't get much school.
多萝西·舒特
北美稀有鸟类
献完血可能会有些头晕
You may be a little dizzy when we're done.
有人来接你吗
Is somebody picking you up?
不  女士  我自己走回去
No, ma'am. Walking back.
你住哪儿
Where do you live?
希尔堡  女士
Fort Hill, ma'am.
那可不近
That's a ways.
就五六英里吧  但我准备从树林穿过去
No. Just five or six miles, but I cut through the woods.
那样要走七英里
It's seven that way!
那你肯定很喜欢大自然
You must really like the woods.
是的  女士  非常喜欢
Yes, ma'am. I sure do.
好了  压住这里
Okay, put some pressure here.
-你还好吗  -嗯
- You okay? - Yeah.
再见
Bye.
你打扮这么精神干什么
Where you going looking all spruced and nice?
昨天在医院认识了一个护士
Met someone yesterday. A nurse over at the hospital.
她叫多萝西·舒特  我要娶她
Her name's Dorothy Schutte. I'm gonna marry her.
天哪  她知道这件事吗
Goodness. Does she know that?
还没  不过快了
Well, not yet. She's about to.
除了家里人  你还跟别的女人说过话吗
You ever even spoken to a woman? I mean, one that's not family.
跟她说过
Spoke to her.
这样的话  来抱抱你哥
Well, in that case, come give your brother a big hug.
-哈哈  -过来
- Hal! - Come here.
把你的油爪子拿开
Keep your greasy paws off of me.
祝我好运吧  老妈
Wish me luck, Momma.
祝你好运
Good luck.
下一个
Next.
请坐  以前献过血吗
Grab a seat. You ever given blood before?
献过  女士
Yes, ma'am. I have.
你是那个皮带小子
You're the belt man.
是戴斯蒙德  女士
Desmond, yes, ma'am.
好吧  戴斯蒙德  两天内不能连续献血
Well, Desmond, we can't take your blood two days in a row.
那挺好  我来把血要回来
Well, that's good. I came to get mine back.
-什么  -我的血  我想要回来
- You what? - My blood. I need it back.
这可不行  我们没法就这么还给你
Well, it don't work like that, we can't just give it back to you.
不行也得行
Well, you got to.
自从你把针插进我的血管
Ever since you stuck me with that needle,
我的心就跳个不停
my heart's been beating real fast.
每次我一想到你  心就跳得更快
Every time I think about you, it beats faster still.
这种话我还真没听过  够肉麻的
I never heard that one before. It's pretty corny.
是吗
It is?
丢死人了  我还练习了一整夜
That's a shame, I done practiced that all night.
很差劲吗
No good?
我可没那么说
I didn't say that.
动脉和静脉有什么区别
What's the difference between an artery and a vein?
-什么意思  -那个小伙子受的伤
- What are you talking about? - The boy's accident.
动脉会喷血
Arteries spurt blood.
静脉呢
And veins?
流血
Bleed.
我觉得你出来前
I think you need to practice
该先在家练习一下约会聊天的话题
your boy/girl dating talk at home before you come out.
是得练练
Yeah, I probably do.
要是你真感兴趣我可以给你本书看
I'll give you a book if you're that interested.
关于约会的吗
On dating?
关于血管
On blood.
美利坚政府
大战的序幕
还有什么医学问题吗
Another medical question perhaps?
没  只觉得你是我生命中最美好的事物
No. I just think you're the prettiest thing I ever seen.
那是因为太暗了看不清
That's because I'm sitting in the dark.
不  你真的很美
No, you're just beautiful.
让开道
Out of the way!
走路要看路
You need to watch where you're going.
抱歉  我以为你不介意
I'm sorry. I didn't think you'd mind.
你问都没问
You didn't ask.
我以为你会喜欢的
I thought you might have liked it.
可能会  但你也得先问啊
Well, I might have if you'd asked.
你不来吗
You coming?
走路看着点儿
Watch where you're walking!
为什么不和我们商量一下
Why didn't you say nothing to us?
你们肯定会千方百计阻止我
'Cause you would have tried and talked me out of it,
而我知道这才是正确的选择
and I know what I'm doing is right.
《摩西十诫》怎么办
And what about His Commandment?
这场战争于我并不是杀戮  而是保护
It's not killing in a war. It's protecting.
咱们教堂里不少青年都报了名
Loads of boys from our church are going.
-是啊  -这场战争需要男人去打
- Yeah. - There is a war and they need men.
在造纸厂工作没法拯救国家
And working in a paper mill ain't going to save this country.
咱儿子看上去就像电影明星
Looks like a movie star, our boy.
漂亮的军装  精致的帽子
Nice uniform, good hat.
让我想起阿蒂·吉登斯
Reminds me of how Artie Giddens
我们在法国那会儿他也这身打扮
looked in his uniform when we went to France.
-还记得他吗  贝莎  -别说了  汤姆
- Remember him, Bertha? - Don't, Tom.
怎么了
What?
我只是说阿蒂穿军装很精神
I'm just saying how snappy Artie looked in his uniform.
你们姑娘们显然也这么觉得
All you girls certainly seemed to think so.
像苍蝇一样围着他  那时他多有面儿啊
He had them flocking to him. He was most proud.
我只希望哈尔被子弹打中时
I just hope that when our Hal gets shot,
子弹是从正面穿过他的夹克
it's through the front of his jacket.
就钻了个眼儿  没弄得血肉模糊
Like a simple entry wound, not much mess.
阿蒂那时被击中后背
Artie got hit in the back,
他的五脏六腑
it blew most of his guts and intestines
从前襟迸裂出来  弄得到处都是
out his front, offal everywhere.
彻底把那身军装给毁了
Wrecked his uniform entirely.
还好他已经死了
It was lucky he was dead,
永远不会知道那身军装看起来有多糟
so he never knew how awful his uniform looked.
别让我看到你
Get outta of my sight.
你是野山羊吗  这么能爬
What are you, part mountain goat?
你是准备帮把手呢  戴斯蒙德·多斯
Are you going to help me, Desmond Doss,
还是让我就这么傻站着
or are you just going to leave me stranded?
我帮你  但要有代价
I'll help you, but it's gonna cost you.
什么
What?
一个吻
A kiss.
-简直就是讹诈  -当然  女士  就是讹你
- That is pure blackmail. - Well, yes, ma'am, it is.
我坚持这么要价
But that is still my condition.
就这么定了  我会督促你执行的
That's the deal. And I'm going to hold you to it.
别急啊
Well, hold on now.
这次不会扇我耳光了吧
You ain't gonna slap me, are you?
我要掉下去  肯定拉你一起
'Cause I fall off, I'm going to take you with me.
吻了才知道
Kiss me and find out.
《坎宁汉实用解剖学手册》
怎么了
What?
我得参军
I have to enlist.
我不能躲在这让其他人为我而战
I can't stay here while all of them go fight for me.
-你可以留下的  -多萝西  我必须去
- Yes, you can. You can stay here. - Dorothy, I have to.
我要做个军医
I want to be a medic.
我想好了  我去救人  而不是杀人
I figure I'll be saving people, not killing them.
我得去上班了  快迟到了
I have to go to work. I'm going to be late.
多萝西  多萝西  亲爱的  多萝西
Dorothy. Dorothy, darling. Dorothy. Dorothy!
你到底要不要向我求婚
So are you going to ask me to marry you or what?
不知道  你还要我吗
Well, I don't know. You still going to have me?
我哪知道  你都还没问
Well, I wouldn't know, you haven't asked.
那我真心实意地问你
Well, I'm asking you, with all my heart and then some.
-你愿意嫁给我吗  -是的  我愿意
- Will you marry me? - Then, yes. Yes, I will.
什么时候
When?
你第一次放假回来的时候
Soon as you get your first leave.
但此时此刻我还是很恨你
But I still don't like you at this moment.
好吧
Okay.
好吧  我可爱你呢
Okay. Well, I love you.
妈说让我来这找你
Momma said come see you here.
嗯
Yeah.
这三个是我最好的朋友
These three were my best friends.
爱德华·米勒
弗吉尼亚州
生于1900年 林奇堡
逝于1918年 贝洛林苑
为国捐躯
和我一起长大
I grew up with 'em,
我们一起惹麻烦  一起泡妞
I got into trouble with 'em, chased girls with 'em.
一起入伍
And I enlisted with 'em.
现在他们躺在那里
Now my friends are there,
埋在草坪底下喂虫子
covered in dirt and grass and eaten by worms.
我不想以后也来这看我儿子
I don't want to have to visit my sons here.
爸  我已经报名了
Daddy, I signed up already.
我别无选择  爸  别人都报了名...
I couldn't do otherwise, Pop. Everybody else is doing...
你又不是别人
You ain't everybody else!
别人只会一股脑扎进去  不经思考
Everybody else jumps in and does things quick, without thinking!
就和我们当年一样蠢
Like the damn idiot fools we were.
而那些活着的士兵
And soldiers who live,
他们能活下来是因为他们有那个本事
they live because they can do that!
可你没有
You can't!
凡事你都得坐下来想半天  还要祷告
Look, you gotta sit and think and pray about everything.
看看  就像你现在这样
I mean, look at you, you're doing it right now.
你要是上了战场  是不可能活着回来的
You won't be able to live with yourself if you go.
不  如果我不去  我没法过自己这关
No, I won't be able to live with myself if I don't.
我要去做一名医务兵  这是我服役的方式
I'm going to be a medic. That's going to be my way to serve.
看看  你就是这样  什么都靠空想
See, there you go, thinking it all out.
怎么  你以为这场战争会围着你转
What, you figure this war
会按照你的意愿进行的吗
is just going to fit in with you, your ideas?
我毫不怀疑肯定会困难重重
Well, I don't doubt it's going to be hard.
不是困难重重  而是根本不可能
It won't be hard, it'll be impossible.
不管你那疯狂的脑子里装着怎样的信仰
You know, whatever beliefs you have in your crazy head now,
一点用都没有  事情不是这么进行的
they won't ever play out. It don't work that way.
要真是出现奇迹  你能活下来
And if by some, I don't know, miracle chance you survive,
你可真要好好感谢上帝了
you won't be giving no thanks to God.
-准备好了吗  -好了
- Ready? - Ready.
你们都需要空间
Y'all need some air.
走吧  小伙子们  你们现在归山姆大叔了
Come on, fellas, shake a leg. Uncle Sam's got you now.
跟你妈妈说再见  快来
Say goodbye to Momma. Come on.
女士们  请离汽车远点儿
Ladies, please, step away from the bus.
-我差点忘了  给  -要我拿铁撬棍吗
- I almost forgot. Here. - Do I need a crowbar?
我想让你拿着这个  这是我的
I want you to have this. It's mine.
你把它带在身边  就像我一直陪着你
You keep it right here, where I'll be.
-再见  -再见
- Bye. - Bye.
我爱你
I love you.
《圣经》
回到我身边
戴斯蒙德·多斯
我爱你
杰克逊堡
别那么说我女朋友
Hey, don't say that about my girl.
-还有什么...  -看着点
- What else... - Hey. Oh.
抱歉  伙计
Hey. Sorry, pal.
说明你就是那个人
...means you're the person.
我每次回自己的床铺都要看见你这畸形吗
Do I have to gaze at your deformity every time I walk to my bed?
你就嫉妒吧  我的朋友
Gaze upon it in envy, my friend.
你还好吧  像丢了魂儿似的  这儿有空位
You okay there? You look lost. Vacancy right here.
明智的选择  在这儿可以看到山和湖
Wise choice. It's got views of the mountains down to the lake.
我叫兰道尔·福勒
Randall Fuller.
戴斯蒙德·多斯
Desmond Doss.
叫他"老师"  他的话没人听得懂
Call him "Teach." No one understands a word he says.
因为这里就没人能认字
That's because no one else here can read.
这位睾丸先生自称"好莱坞"
The testicles there belong to a man calling himself "Hollywood."
不过型号看起来该属于体型更小的人
They look like they belong to a smaller guy.
你还挺了解睾丸啊
You know testicles.
我才刚领的鞋
Oh! Hey, I just got these shoes.
格里斯·诺兰  来自红钩区
Hey, uh, Grease Nolan, outta Red Hook.
你是从哪儿来的
Where you from?
-弗吉尼亚  -乡巴佬啊
- Virginia. - Ooh, hillbilly, huh?
你娶了你的表亲吗  我开玩笑的
You marry your first cousin? I'm just joking.
那是史密提  在让卡赞斯基出丑
That's Smitty over there, whipping Kirzinski's ass.
说得好像你多能干似的  笨蛋
Like you were doing any better, chowder head.
我那是不想让你难堪
Hey, I didn't want to embarrass you.
沃尔·卡赞斯基  很高兴认识你
Wal Kirzinski, nice to meet you.
瘦竹竿  你说你叫什么来着
Hey, beanpole, what did you say your name was?
戴斯蒙德·多斯
Desmond Doss.
那是特克斯·刘易斯  他以为自己是个牛仔
That's Tex Lewis over there, he thinks he's some kind of cowboy.
还有维多· 雷纳利
And, uh, Vito Rinnelli.
别看他个子小  他可不好惹
He may be small, but he is a bulldog.
-你好  -你好
- Hey. - How you doing?
戴斯蒙德
Desmond.
这边这个帅小伙是卢奇·福特
This handsome guy right here is Lucky Ford.
你好
Hey.
那是沃克和皮尼克
That's Walker and Pinnick
他们在假装自己是老千
over there pretending they're card sharks.
格里斯[意同油脂]  消停点儿行吗
Pipe down, Grease, all right?
你是不是想把钱塞进自己嘴里
Unless you want to put your money where your mouth is.
一本古老的好书啊  是吧
Oh, hey, the old good book, right?
卢奇好像也有本好书
I think Lucky's got a good book.
-是吧  卢奇  -这可是好书
- Right, Lucky? - It's a good read.
集合
Attention!
排好队  动起来
Line up! Move it!
快  动起来  动起来
Let's go, move it. Move it.
如果你不介意的话
You are a very strange-looking individual
我要说你长得真奇怪  二等兵
if you don't mind me saying so, Private.
-你的名字  -安迪·沃克
- Name? - Andy Walker.
你死了多久了  小子
How long have you been dead, son?
-长官  -我不是"长官"
- Sir? - I am not "Sir"!
我是霍威尔中士  你也可以叫我中士
I am Sergeant Howell or Sarge.
长官你还是留着喊那些废物吧
"Sir" you save for useless people.
你说你叫"食尸鬼"吗
The name is "Ghoul," You say?
沃克  中士
Walker, Sergeant!
-就叫食尸鬼了  -是  长官
- Ghoul it is. - Yes, Sergeant!
你的样子有些不对  二等兵
There's something off in your presentation, Private.
我说不清
Can't place it.
是你的头发吗
Is it your hair?
还是你裤子上的褶皱
Is it the wrinkle in your trousers?
我脚上插了一把刀  中士
I have a knife in my foot, Sergeant.
当然了  就是这个  刀子
Oh, yes, of course, that's it. The knife.
-士兵  你叫什么  -史密提·莱克
- What is your name, soldier? - Smitty Ryker.
不  你叫二等兵蠢蛋  你知道为什么吗
No, your name is Private Idiot. Do you know why?
因为我脚上插着一把刀
Because I have a knife in my foot.
谁把刀插上去的  二等兵
Who placed the knife there, Private?
这是意外  中士  我们在玩儿掷刀子
It was an accident, Sarge. We was playing Stretch.
我真欣慰
I am heartened by the knowledge
你不是故意把刀插上去的
you did not place it there with intention.
谁扔的刀
Who threw the knife?
是我  中士  二等兵卡赞斯基
I did, Sergeant. Private Kirzinski.
你长得像印第安人  哪个部落的  小子
You look part Indian. To what tribe do you belong, son?
不  我是波兰人
No, I'm Polish.
不对
Wrong.
你身上一定流着切诺基人或肖尼族人的血
I believe you must have Cherokee or Shawnee blood in you.
-不  中士  -你是在顶撞我吗
- No, Sergeant. - Are you contradicting me,
-你这个婊子养的东西  -不  中士
- you wagon-burning son of a bitch? - No, Sergeant!
让我看看你印第安式的呐喊
Let me see your Indian war cry, son.
我不是
I don't...
大点儿声  让我看看
Louder! Let me see it.
你的兽性呢  你是袜带蛇吗
What is your animal spirit? Are you a garter snake?
-不是  中士  -你是花栗鼠吗
- No, Sergeant! - Are you a chipmunk?
-不是  中士  -那你是跳舞的驯鹿吗
- No, Sergeant! - Are you a dancing reindeer?
-不  中士  -你在顶撞我吗  二等兵
- No, Sergeant! - Are you contradicting me, Private?
-不是  中士  -很好
- No, Sergeant! - Good.
那以后我以后就叫你"酋长"了
Then I shall henceforth call you "Chief"
以显示我对你们部落的尊重
as a sign of great respect to your people.
谢谢  中士
Thank you, Sergeant!
你在冲我傻笑吗  小子  还是你平时就这样
Are you grinning at me, boy, or is that your natural state?
不  中士
No, Sergeant.
-你的名字  二等兵  -戴斯蒙德·多斯
- Name, Private? - Desmond Doss.
我见过一些玉米杆都比你结实
I have seen stalks of corn with better physiques.
让我想把你的耳朵拧下来  二等兵
Makes me want to pull an ear off, Private.
-你能撑住你的重量吗  -能  中士
- Can you carry your weight? - Yes, Sergeant!
那对你来说应该很容易了
Should be easy for you, then.
-下士  -中士
- Corporal. - Sergeant.
刮大风的时候看好你的兵
Make sure you keep this man away from strong winds.
是  中士
Yes, Sergeant.
-二等兵蠢蛋  -是  中士
- Private Idiot. - Yes, Sergeant.
抬起你的脚来  抬高点
Raise your foot. Higher.
所有人都出去  现在  赶快
Everyone outside. Now! Move it.
我说了  动起来
I said move it.
好的  我先穿上制服  中士
All right. Just getting in my uniform, Sarge.
我让他穿了吗  下士
Did I ask him to, Corporal?
没有  中士
No memory of it, Sarge.
我相信能如此以裸体为傲的人
I believe any man who takes such pride in his natural naked state
也必然能享受外面的寒风
will surely enjoy the brisk of the outdoors.
动起来  光屁股先生
Now move your privates, Private Parts!
动起来  你这个裸露狂
Move it! You son of an exhibitionist!
现在我来教你们怎么打单套结
I am going to teach you how to tie a bowline knot,
这样你们就能从高处爬下来
so you can get your sorry asses down from a height,
好让我踢你们的屁股
so I may then kick them!
打个圈  这是兔子洞
Create a loop. This is the rabbit hole.
兔子从里面钻出来  绕过树
The rabbit comes out of his hole, runs around the tree,
回到洞里  好了  你们试一下
goes back into the hole. All right, let's go!
很好  特克斯
Very good, Tex.
继续努力  老师
Keep struggling, Teach.
你栓过羊吗  好莱坞
Have you ever roped a goat, Hollywood?
没有  中士
No, Sarge.
你看过山羊的眼睛吗
Have you ever looked into a goat's eyes?
-没有  中士  -很好  不然太奇怪了
- No, Sarge. - Good, that would be unnatural.
你知道如果你不呼吸  你就会死
You know if you don't breathe, you'll die.
很好  二等兵蠢蛋
Good, Private Idiot.
恭喜你  油脂球
Congratulations, Greaseball,
你刚从15米高的地方掉下来摔断了脖子
you just fell 50 feet and broke your neck!
很好  二等兵维多·雷纳利
Brilliant, Private Vito Rinnelli.
你把自己勒死了  你个白痴
You strangled yourself, numb nuts!
-你是贝尼托的粉丝吗  -不是  中士
- Are you a fan of Benito? - No, Sergeant.
长高点儿  身为美国人  你得长高点儿
A bit taller. If you were American, you'd be taller.
你这是什么玩意儿  多斯  一边乳头一个吗
What've we got here, Doss, one for each titty?
我是让你们打单套结  不是做胸罩
You were tying a bowline, boy, not building a bra!
有什么好笑的吗  下士
What is so funny, Corporal?
我不知道  中士
Couldn't tell you, Sergeant.
快点  姑娘们  跟上  跑起来
Come on! Come on, ladies, pick it up! Move it! Move it!
让我看到你们的激情  加把劲儿
I want to see some fire here. A little hustle.
让我看看
Show me something!
认真点跑起来
Run like you mean it!
低点  低点儿  快点  再快点儿
Down, down, down! Faster, faster!
加把劲儿  动起来
Come on. Move it! Move it!
走吧  该洗澡了  小子们  洗澡时间到
Let's go, it's bath time, boys! It's bath time!
动起来  动起来
Move! Move! Move!
让我看看你们的努力  快
I want to see you work. Let's go!
挖 挖  挖啊
Dig, dig, dig!
别忘了洗洗耳朵后面  快  动起来
Don't forget behind your ears. Let's go. Move!
我赌你一定很喜欢这个  光屁股的原始人
I bet you're enjoying this, you naked degenerate.
快走  快  快  动起来
Let's go! Hustle. Hustle. Hustle. Move!
走吧  还等什么  走  动起来
Let's go! What are we waiting on? Let's go! Move your ass!
到木墙那里去  去翻墙  别碰那些碎片
Get the wood! Get the wall! Don't get splinters!
动起来
Drive!
天  你没事吧
Jeez, are you okay?
我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
加把劲儿  小伙子们  动起来
Some spirit here, boys. Move!
快  动起来
Come on, move!
你怎么回事  没人让你休息
What the hell is wrong with you? No one said take a rest!
快冲过终点  快跑  快
Move your asses to the finish line! Move! Move!
快  快
Hustle! Hustle!
撅起屁股冲过那条线
Get your asses across that line!
计时  干得漂亮  多斯
Time! Nice work, Doss!
这是美国政府送给你们的私人礼物
This is a personal gift from the United States government
人人都有
to each and every one of you.
一把标配的M1式美国步枪  口径0.30
A standard issue U.S. Rifle, caliber .30, M1,
自动上膛的肩扛式半自动步枪
a clip-fed, shoulder-fired, semi-automatic weapon
专门用来摧毁敌人  给他们带去死亡的
designed to bring death and destruction to the enemy.
它会是你的爱人  你的情人  你的小老婆
This is to be your lover, your mistress, your concubine.
也许会是你一生中唯一的真爱
Perhaps the only thing in life you will ever truly love.
小伙子们  开始跳舞了  选一个女伴吧
Fellas, let's dance. Grab a girl.
别把你的枪口朝前
Don't point your gun forward.
我今天还不想死
I do not want to be shot today.
你们就不要白费心思了
No matter how much you are tempted.
把枪立在一边
Place the weapon by your side.
注意
Pay attention.
你有什么问题吗  二等兵玉米杆
Problem, Private Corn Stalk?
没有适合你的尺寸吗
Is there not one in your size,
还是你不喜欢这个颜色
or is it the color that is the issue?
不  中士
No, Sarge.
他们说我可以不带武器
I was... I was told I don't have to carry a weapon.
再说一次  站出来  二等兵  我肯定听错了
Come again? Step forward, Private. I can't be hearing this right.
对不起  中士
Well, I'm sorry, Sergeant.
我不能碰枪
I can't touch a gun.
到底有什么问题
What exactly is the problem?
没什么  只是搞错了  长官
No problem, just a mistake, sir.
我参军时告诉过部队的人
I told the Army when I joined up.
不可能
That's not possible.
你知道为什么不可能吗  二等兵
Do you know why it's not possible, Private?
不知道  长官
No, sir.
因为美国军队从不犯错
Because the United States Army does not make mistakes.
所以如果有问题  那一定出在你身上
So if there's a problem, you must be that problem.
他们不应该把我送到步枪连
I was just never supposed to be sent to a rifle company.
他是因道义原因拒服兵役者  长官
He's a C.O., sir.
格洛弗上尉
因为道义而拒服兵役  而你却来参了军
You're a conscientious objector, and you joined the Army?
不  长官  我是个尽责的合作者
Well, no, sir, I'm a conscientious cooperator.
你在拿我消遣吗  多斯
Are you screwing with me, Doss?
不  长官  我是自愿参军的
No. No, sir. I volunteered.
我可以穿军装
I ain't got no problem with wearing my uniform,
也可以朝国旗敬礼  并履行我的义务
or saluting the flag and doing my duty.
只是我不能拿枪和杀人
It's just carrying a gun and the taking of human life.
你不杀人  仅此而已
You don't kill? That's all.
是的  长官  仅此而已
Yes, sir, that's all.
你知道战争总是会让很多人送命吧
You know quite a bit of killing does occur in a war?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
这才是战争的真谛
I mean, that is the essential nature of war.
-是  长官  -好吧
- Yes, sir. - All right.
你对美国军队还有什么其他要求吗
Do you have any other requirements of the United States Army?
我们还有什么其他要注意的吗
Is there anything else that we can do to ensure
好让你觉得和我们在一起舒服点儿
that you have a comfortable stay here with us?
他周六不想工作  长官
He doesn't want to work on Saturdays, sir.
周六  是这样的
Well, Saturdays...
我是基督七日复临安息日会的信徒
I'm a Seventh-day Adventist.
周六是安息日  所以我不能工作
So, Saturday is my Sabbath, so I'm not allowed to work then.
这应该没有什么问题吧  中士
I don't think that poses a problem, do you, Sergeant?
我们应该直接告诉敌人周六不要进攻
We shall simply ask the enemy not to invade on the Sabbath,
因为二等兵多斯要在这天祷告
'cause Private Doss here is at prayer.
好吧  我明白了
All right. Now we got that clear.
现在让我来说说我的要求吧
Now let me tell you my requirements.
我的要求没有你那么复杂  我的要求很简单
They're not as complicated as yours. They're very simple.
只要你在这个连队里一天  在我的指挥之下
As long as you're in this company, under my command,
你就必须遵循我的命令  就是这样
you will obey my orders. Period.
如果你在这里都做不到
If you can't do it here,
我无法相信你在战场上能做到
I can't trust you to do it in battle.
我会用第八条例  让你因精神问题而退伍
I'm putting you in for a Section 8, psychiatric discharge.
解散
Dismissed.
先生们
Gentlemen!
我想让你们认识一下二等兵戴斯蒙德·多斯
I want you to meet Private Desmond Doss.
显然二等兵多斯不喜欢暴力
Apparently, Private Doss does not believe in violence.
他拒绝使用暴力
He does not practice violence.
他甚至不肯屈尊去触碰武器
He will not even deign to touch a weapon.
二等兵多斯是个因道义原因拒服兵役者
You see, Private Doss is a conscientious objector.
我恳请你们
So I plead with you, do not
别指望他在战场上救你们
look to him to save you on the battlefield,
因为他那时一定忙着
because he will undoubtedly be
和他所谓的良知作斗争呢
too busy wrestling with his conscience to assist.
中士  不是这样的
Sarge, that's not true.
二等兵  你明明就是
Private, as you were.
我知道你们也许有人对此颇有看法
Now, I realize some of you might have strong feelings about this.
这就是我们参战的原因
It is what we men fight for.
捍卫我们的权利  保护我们的女人和孩子们
To defend our rights, and to protect our women and children.
尽管二等兵多斯的信仰
Even if Private Doss'
可能会让女人们和孩子们无辜死去
beliefs might cause women and children to die.
我希望连队里的每个人都能
So I will expect everyone in this company
在二等兵多斯仅剩不多的跟我们共处的时间内
to give Private Doss the full measure of respect he is due
给他充分的尊重
for the short time he will be with us.
听明白了吗
Am I clear?
是  中士
Yes, Sergeant.
看看这是什么  小多斯
What'cha got there, Dessie?
你知道那是什么
You know what that is.
只是看起来有点小
It just seems kind of small.
给小人用的小圣经
It's half the Bible for half the man.
看在上帝的份上  史密提  把圣经还给他
For Pete's sake, Smitty, give him back his Bible.
我好像没跟你说话吧
I don't remember speaking to you.
你为什么不作战  你以为你高人一等吗
So, how come you don't fight? You think you're better than us?
不
No.
如果有人攻击你怎么办
What if you was attacked?
就像这样
Say, like that.
圣经上说  还要把另一边脸送上去  对吗
The Bible says to turn the other cheek, don't it?
你看  我觉得这不是宗教问题  小子
See, I don't think this is a question of religion, fellas.
我觉得这是怯懦  就这么简单
I think this is cowardice, plain and simple.
-对吗  多斯  -你是个胆小鬼  对吗
- Is that right, Doss? - Are you chickenshit, that it?
来啊  动手啊
Go on, take a poke.
告诉你  我让你白打一下
Tell you what, I'm going to give you a free shot.
来吧  这儿
Right there.
动手啊  多斯  打我
Hit me, Doss. Go on.
-揍他  -上啊
- Let him have it. - Go ahead.
不打吗
No?
胆小鬼
Chickenshit.
等一下  这是什么
Hold on here. What is this?
还给我
Give me that.
-是个漂亮妞  -真不赖
- This is a fine-looking broad. - Nice.
传给大家看看
Hey, pass it around.
这种小妞儿就得让真男人驾驭
Now, this would be the kind of broad that deserves a real man.
还给我
Give me that back.
要说请
Please.
请
请还给我  史密提
"Please give it back, Smitty."
Please give it back, Smitty.
你有幻听吗  戴斯蒙德
Do you hear voices, Desmond?
没有  长官
No, sir.
但据我理解  上帝会跟你对话  是吗
But I understand that God talks to you. Is that right?
长官  我没疯
Sir, I'm not a crazy person.
你觉得大家都认为你是疯子吗
Is that how you feel most people regard you, a crazy person?
我知道  我和其他人不同  但是...
I'm different. I know that, but...
我也不打算装疯卖傻
I'm not going to pretend to be something I'm not.
-我就是我  -听起来有点孤独
- I am what I am. - Sounds lonely.
你觉得孤独吗
You lonely?
-你没有幻听  -是的长官
- So, you don't hear voices. - No, sir.
我会祷告  并希望上帝听到了我的祈祷
I pray to God and I like to think He hears me,
但祷告不是对话
but it ain't a conversation,
像我们俩现在就是在假装对话
like the one we're pretending to have right now.
-假装吗  二等兵  -是的  长官
- Pretending, Private? - Well, yes, sir.
我知道您想说
I know all you really want to
我有精神问题  好打发我退伍
do is give me a Section 8, drum me out of the Army,
但我脑子没问题  我只是坚持信仰而已
but I'm not off up above. I just simply believe what I believe.
我在试着理解你  好吗
Well, I'm trying to understand, all right?
是上帝告诉你不能拿枪的吗
Was it God who told you not to pick up a rifle?
上帝说  不可杀人
God says not to kill.
这是他最重要的诫示
That's one of His most important Commandments.
大部分人理解为  不可谋杀别人
Most people take that to mean, "Don't commit murder."
战争可完全不一样
War is a completely different set of circumstances.
耶稣说 我赐给你们一条新命令
Jesus said, "A new Commandment
乃是叫你们彼此相爱
I give unto you,
我怎样爱你们  你们也要怎样相爱
that you love one another, just as I have loved you."
但我们面对的是撒旦
This is Satan himself we're fighting.
作为虔诚的基督徒  你当然能明白吧
Surely, as a good Christian, you can see that.
我明白  长官  所以我报名参了军
I can see that, sir, and that is why I joined up.
但很抱歉  我不携带武器
But I'm sorry, I will not bear arms.
他的宗教观点很独特
His religious views are certainly unique,
但是并不符合第八条例的开除军籍规定
but they do not constitute grounds for a Section 8 discharge.
有个这样的人在
How am I supposed to maintain
我还怎么管理连队
discipline with a man like that in my unit?
我也不知道
I don't know.
但他是正当的因道义原因拒服兵役者
But he is a legitimate conscientious objector,
只要他的各项训练达标
and he must be allowed to work as a combat medic,
就不能拒绝他成为一名战地医护人员
provided he qualifies in all other areas of his training.
也许我们可以帮忙让他信点别的
Perhaps we could help make believe in his idea.
对  让他去清扫营房  当帮厨
Yeah, you restrict him to barracks and KP.
他跟你聊上帝  你就送他下地狱
If he throws God at you, you throw hell right at him.
把他赶走
I want him gone.
多斯  你的内务太丢脸了  这是猪圈
Doss, your area is a disgrace. It's a pig sty!
-好笑吗  莱克  -不  中士
- Something funny, Ryker? - No, Sarge!
-你脑子里糊了屎吗  -没有  中士
- You got some shit on your mind? - No, Sarge!
你们都没有意识到的是
What you men fail to recognize
一颗老鼠屎会坏一锅汤
is a unit is no better than its weakest member!
为了让大家明白
Now, to help you learn that lesson,
本周末不准外出
there will be no passes this weekend.
你们都要去当帮厨
You will all be on KP!
现在  全副武装准备开始30公里拉练
Right now, everybody in full gear for a 20-mile hike.
快点  出发
Let's go! Let's go.
昂首挺胸
Get your heads right.
别可怜你们自己
Don't start feeling sorry for yourself.
看到你们可怜自己我会恶心
Makes me sick see you feel sorry for yourself.
你们这些畜生根本没见识过什么是累
You dogs don't know what tired is.
我不说停谁都别想休息
We're going to keep going till I drop.
够了  还让不让人睡觉了
Hey, knock it off. Trying to sleep here.
-走开  别碰我  -好  好吧
- Get off me. Get off me. - Okay. All right.
你他妈为什么不走呢
Why the hell are you still here?
原地立定
As you were.
多斯呢
Where's Doss?
这样对谁都不好
This isn't good for anybody.
我当初参军肯定不是为了这样
Sure ain't what I joined up for.
这跟你参军的目的无关
It's not about what you joined up for.
这关乎到每个人的性命
It's about the lives of every man in here.
还有你自己的命  孩子  是时候退出了
And yours, son. It's time to quit this.
穿好衣服  我带你走
Finish getting dressed and I'll walk you down.
没事的  多斯
It's okay, Doss.
没什么不好意思的
There's no shame in this.
走吧
Let's go.
我今天还要站岗  今早还要去帮厨...
I got extra guard duty today, and I'm on KP this morning, so...
我不能走
Can't.
好吧  多斯
All right, Doss.
二等兵多斯  你能认出是谁打了你吗
Private Doss, can you identify the men that beat you?
不知道  长官
No, Sarge.
你是说你不知道被谁打了吗
Are you saying that you don't know who attacked you?
我从来没说过有人打我  长官
I never said I was attacked, Sarge.
你在说什么胡话  多斯
Well, what the hell are you saying, Doss?
你睡觉的时候把自己弄得满身是伤吗
You bruised half your body sleeping?
我  我睡觉很不老实
I... I sleep pretty hard.
好吧
Alright.
如果这周末有什么湿身计划
If you plan on getting wet this weekend,
记得做好保护措施
make sure you put on a hat.
下一位
Next.
可不想有谁回来弄得下体感染[尿的东西像奶油]
Don't want anyone coming back pissing cream.
怎么  你的咖啡里不想来点吗  中士
What, you don't want none for your coffee, Sarge?
要不就现在吧  史密提
How about a shot right now, Smitty?
-你这是经验之谈吗  中士  -下一位
- You speaking from experience, Sarge? - Next.
那得问你老妈了  油脂球
You'd have to ask your mom about that, Greaseball.
稍息
At ease.
二等兵多斯  恐怕不能给你出入证了
Private Doss, I'm afraid I can't authorize your pass.
只有通过了基础训练的人才能出去
This is a furlough for men who have passed the basic training.
长官  无意冒犯  我通过了
Well, sir, respectfully, sir, I have.
我三周前就申请了出入证
I put in for this furlough three weeks ago.
我今天下午要结婚
I'm getting married this afternoon.
上面写着你的射击不合格
It says you're not rifle qualified.
我不用配枪
Well, I'm not required to carry a rifle,
施特尔策上校  他说...
sir. Colonel Stelzer, he...
施特尔策上校的决定是...
Colonel Stelzer's determination was...
"如果多斯的其他各项训练都达标
"Doss must be allowed to work as a combat medic,
就可以成为战地医护人员"
provided he qualifies in all other areas of his training."
但你的射击训练不合格
And you have not qualified on the rifle range, Private.
清晰明了
Pretty clear.
要不你现在就证明
Show me you know how to
你知道怎么用枪  我就批准你外出
handle a rifle and I'll sign your furlough.
-卡农下士  -是
- Corporal Cannon. - Sir!
把你的武器给二等兵多斯
Hand Private Doss your firearm.
我不碰枪  长官
I won't touch a rifle, sir.
我不是征求你的意见  二等兵
I'm not asking you, Private!
这是来自连长的直接命令
That is a direct order from a company commander.
拜托  多斯  别再挣扎了  走吧
For God's sake, Doss, you stop this nonsense and quit.
如果你拒绝  我就只能把你送上军事法庭了
Refuse, and I will have no recourse but to court-martial you,
战争期间  你将在军事监狱度过
and you will spend the duration of the war in a military prison.
我不能碰枪  长官
I can't, sir.
还要等多久  多萝西
How much longer would you like to wait, Dorothy?
已经够久了
I think it's been long enough.
我很遗憾
I'm so very sorry.
有时候男人会临阵脱逃
Sometimes men just get cold feet.
也许其他男人会  但我的戴斯蒙德不会
Some men might. Not my Desmond.
你可能觉得我是个彻头彻尾的混蛋
You probably think I'm a real son of a bitch
只关心规定  不关心士兵
who cares only about regulations and not his men.
我能看看吗
May I?
我和任何人一样信仰这本书
I believe in this book as much as any man.
我也和任何人一样  跟自己的良心斗争
And just like any man, I wrestle with my conscience,
但如果
but what do you do when
你珍惜的一切都在遭受袭击怎么办
everything you value in this world is under attack?
我不知道  长官
I don't know, sir.
我回答不了这么大的问题
I ain't got answers to questions that big,
但我也觉得我的价值观受到了攻击
but I also feel like my values are under attack,
但我不知道原因
and I don't know why.
我根本不关心你的信仰
I don't give a rat's ass
因为日本人不会关心
about your principles because the Japs don't.
如果他们袭击你和伤员
If one of them attacks you and some wounded soldier,
你怎么办
what are you gonna do?
用圣经敲他们的头吗
Hit him with your Bible?
我可以为了战友付出生命
I'm prepared to give my life for my men.
光靠牺牲可赢不了战争
You don't win wars by giving up your life.
我来这里是因为
Look, I'm only here because I
我不想你一直在监牢里等死
don't want to see you rotting in a prison cell.
认罪吧  请求法庭宽大处理
Plead guilty, throw yourself at the mercy of the court.
也许他们会放你回家祷告
Maybe they'll let you go home and pray.
让真正的勇士去冲锋陷阵  血战沙场
Let the brave men out there go and win this war.
如果我还是说服不了你  也许她可以
If I can't convince you, maybe she can.
他们不让我给你打电话
They wouldn't let me call you.
我知道不是你的错
I knew it wasn't your making.
他们都怎么对你了
What have they done to you?
我没事  我还好
It's okay, I'm all right.
只是对着墙壁发泄了一会儿
I just went a couple of rounds with the wall and lost.
他们说你可能会进监狱  戴斯蒙德
They're saying you could go to prison, Desmond.
去莱文沃斯[美国城市]
Leavenworth.
肯定还有别的方法
There must be some other way.
我不知道还能有什么办法
I don't know what that could be.
除了用枪  我每件事都照办了
I've done everything they asked me, except this one thing,
就因为我不杀人  他们就把我当成罪犯关着
and I'm being treated like a criminal just 'cause I won't kill.
你努力了  没人能否认这点
You tried. Nobody can say you didn't.
可在监狱里你还能救谁呢
But who are you going to save in prison?
可能谁也救不了
Probably nobody.
那你为什么不能
Then why can't you just
拿起那该死的枪让他们看看呢
pick up the stupid gun and wave it around?
不是让你用枪杀人  只是妥协一点
You don't have to use it, just meet them halfway.
-我不能  -你可以的  你只是太骄傲
- I can't do that. - Yes, you can. It's just pride.
骄傲又倔强  别让上帝影响你的想法
Pride and stubbornness. Don't confuse your will with the Lord's.
我骄傲吗
Have I been prideful?
也许是吧
Maybe I am prideful.
但如果我不能坚持自己的信仰
But I don't know how I'm going to live with myself
我不知道该如何面对自己
if I don't stay true to what I believe.
更不知道怎么面对你
Much less how you could live with me.
那样我就不是你眼中的我了
I'd never be the man that I want to be in your eyes.
我爱你是因为你和别人都不一样
I fell in love with you because you weren't like anyone else
你也不曾试图跟他们一样
and you didn't try to be.
千万别觉得你会让我失望
Do not think for one moment that you will disappoint me.
无论如何  我都爱你
I will love you no matter what.
我也不知道他会怎么做  不管怎样他都是输
I don't know what he's gonna do. He loses no matter what.
他们想让他认罪
They want him to plead guilty,
那他就会被开除军籍
but then he'll get a dishonorable discharge.
要不就坚持  那肯定就会进监狱
Otherwise he fights them, and he for sure goes to prison.
不论怎样  他们都认为他是懦夫
Either way, they'll call him a coward
我不知道他怎么接受得了
and I don't see how he can live with that.
谢谢  多萝西
Well, thank you, Dorothy.
如果你能跟他说上话
If you get to talk to him,
告诉他  我们爱他  为他祈祷
tell him that we love him and that we're praying for him.
为你们两个祈祷
We're praying for both of you.
我会的  再见
I will. Bye-bye.
汤姆  你疯了吗
Tom, you're out of your mind, you're delirious.
我当然疯了
Of course, I'm out of my mind.
你以为呢  我就是疯了
What do you think I am? I'm out of my mind.
你出去
You leave this room.
不  汤姆  放下枪
No, Tom! Put it down!
走开  你这个女人
Get away from me, woman!
我来吧  先生
I got that, sir.
有什么可以帮您的  先生
May I help you, sir?
我想见默斯格罗夫准将
I wish to speak to Brigadier General Musgrove.
预约过才可以
Not without an appointment you can't.
您不能见
That would be quite impossible.
能不能麻烦你告诉他
Uh, if you would kindly tell him
托马斯·多斯下士想跟他说两句话
Corporal Thomas Doss would appreciate a brief word.
他在参加一个重要会议
He's in a very important meeting.
我在法国北洛森林跟着他打过仗  他是队长
I fought with him in France at Belleau Wood. He was my captain.
拜托了  女士  这事非常重要
Please, ma'am, it's most vital.
谢谢你  女士
Thank you, ma'am.
外面有个人找你  叫汤姆·多斯
There's a man out there, Tom Doss.
多斯
Doss?
很快就结束了
Be over in a minute.
你可以像什么都没发生过一样回家了
You'll be home safe and sound, like nothing ever happened.
我爱你
I love you.
这是关于二等兵戴斯蒙德·多斯的听证会
This is a hearing into the matter of Private Desmond Doss.
罪名是违反上级的
The charge is disobeying a series of direct orders
一系列直接命令
from his commanding officer.
辩方有何观点
How says the defendant?
二等兵多斯想进行无罪辩护
Private Doss wishes to enter a "Not guilty" Plea.
是吗  我以为已经达成协议了
Is that so, Private? I thought this was agreed.
你要进行认罪求情呢
You wanted to enter some sort of plea bargain.
-是的  但我改变主意了  -是吗
- Yes, sir, but I changed my mind. - Just like that?
你想上军事法庭
You wish to proceed to a court-martial?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
那就随你吧  二等兵  继续
Well, on your head, then, Private. Proceed.
法官大人  二等兵多斯用道德压我们
Your Honor, Private Doss waves his morality at us
好像那是他的荣耀勋章一样
like it's some kind of badge of honor.
他公然蔑视
He flaunts his contempt by
违反了长官的
directly disobeying a series of direct orders
一系列直接命令
from his commanding officer.
而我们的其他士兵
When the very best of our
还在沙场上浴血奋战...
young men are sacrificing their lives against...
-你还好吗  -没事
- You okay? - Yes.
他们还在审理吗
Are they still deliberating?
是的
Yes, sir.
好  你把这个拿进去
Okay, now you go take this in there.
不行  只有军队人员才能进入
I can't. It's strictly military personnel.
那就让他们帮忙拿进去
Well, then you get one of them to take it in.
他们不会帮忙的  他们恨不得直接埋了他
They ain't out to help. They're fixing to bury him.
任何军事法庭
There is only one question
都只需要问被告一个问题
that any military court need ask of the accused.
你是否否认违反了萨斯顿上校的直接命令
Do you deny disobeying Colonel Sangston's direct orders?
你否认吗  二等兵
Well, do you, Private?
-不  我不否认  -那还有什么好争辩的呢
- No, sir. I don't. - Why are you contesting it, then?
既然你都拒绝碰枪了
Why is it so important to you,
为什么在部队服役
given your refusal to even touch a weapon,
对你还那么重要呢
to serve in a combat unit?
因为日本袭击珍珠港的时候
Because when the Japanese
我很生气
attacked Pearl Harbor, I took it personal.
我身边的所有人都迫切想参军  包括我
Everyone I knew was on fire to join up, including me.
我家乡有两个人被判定不适合服役
There were two men in my home town... declared 4-F unfit.
他们为此而自杀了
They killed themselves because they couldn't serve.
我在国防工厂上班  本可以推迟服役
I had a job in a defense plant and I could've taken a deferment,
但那是不对的
but that ain't right.
其他人可以战斗  牺牲
It isn't right that other men should fight and die,
而我在家安享太平是不对的
that I would just be sitting at home safe.
我必须参军
I need to serve.
我充满激情想做一个战地医护人员
I got the energy and the passion to serve as a medic.
和其他人并肩作战  同样浴血沙场  只是
Right in the middle with the other guys. No less danger, just...
其他人夺取生命的时候  我是去救人性命
While everybody else is taking life, I'm going to be saving it.
当世界四分五裂的时候
With the world so set on tearing itself apart,
我觉得想努力把它拼凑起来
it doesn't seem like such a bad thing to me
并没什么不对
to want to put a little bit of it back together.
抱歉先生  任何人不得进入...
Sorry, sir, nobody's allowed to go...
不  你不明白  我儿子是被告
No, you don't understand. My son is the defendant.
我明白先生  但任何人都不能
I understand, sir, but nobody's allowed...
我手上有很重要的信息
I have information that's important.
先生  您不能进
Sir, you are not allowed...
虽然表现出来的情感值得称赞
While the sentiments expressed are laudable,
但是指控罪名看起来也无可辩驳  因此...
the facts of the charge seem incontestable, so...
外面什么情况
What the hell is going on out there?
放开他
Let him go.
-你穿的是一战的军装  -是的长官
- That's a Great War uniform. - It is, sir.
长官  这个必须给您
Sir, I need to show you this.
但是  先生  你已经不是军人了
With respect, sir, you are no longer a member of the military.
你不能参加听证会  抱歉
You are unable to attend this hearing. I'm sorry.
真是这样吗  长官
Is that truly the way it works, sir?
你为祖国而战
You fight for your country,
失去了那么多珍贵的东西
you lose so much that was dear to you,
然后你就被抛弃了吗
and then you're done with?
军装被遗忘  你再也无力发声
The uniform is forgotten. You have no voice.
你在利斯河战斗过
You were at Lys?
是的  长官  还有贝洛森林
I was, sir. And at Belleau Wood.
两次授勋啊
Twice decorated, I see.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
我想你就是这位列兵的父亲吧
I take it you are the Private's father.
是的  长官  托马斯·多斯
I am, sir. Thomas Doss.
那么作为退役军人  你该明白法律规定
Then, as a former military man, you know there are laws here...
长官  我懂法  也知道我儿子也受其保护
Sir, I know the law and I know my son is protected by those laws.
宪法中是这样规定的
They are framed in our constitution.
他也和我一样  信任这法律
And I believe in them, as he does.
我上战场就是为它而战
They are why I went and fought to protect them.
至少我以为是如此
At least, that is what I thought I was doing.
因为如果不是为此
Because if it wasn't for that,
那我也不知道我是去为何而战了  长官
then I have no idea what the hell I was doing there, sir.
谢谢  多斯下士
Thank you, Corporal Doss.
把信给我吧
Let me have the letter.
你必须离开了
You must go.
"作为良知拒绝服役者  被告享有
"The defendant's rights as a conscientious objector
为国会法案保护的权利
are protected by an Act of Congress
无人有权强迫他放弃他的权利
and he cannot be compelled to waive those rights.
此案中其包括  他拒绝携带武器的权利"
That includes, in this case, his disobeying orders to bear arms."
签名  战时指挥官
Signed, Brigadier General Musgrove,
默斯格罗夫准将  华盛顿特区
War Services Commander, Washington, D.C.
上校
Colonel?
-我撤销指控  长官  -那么案件驳回
- I withdraw the charges, sir. - Then this case is dismissed.
二等兵多斯  你有权不携带任何
Private Doss, you are free to run into the hellfire of battle
用以自保的武器冲上战场
without a single weapon to protect yourself.
你将恢复原职  并开始军医培训
You may resume your duties and begin training as a combat medic.
-他在哪  -走了  直接走的
- Where is he? - Gone. Straight after.
我求他留下  我说了你会想见他
I begged him to stay. I told him you'd want to see him.
没事  我理解
No, I understand.
等你回家  告诉他我爱他
When you get home, you tell him I love him.
好的  好的
Okay. Okay.
你可不许不回来
You better come home to me.
冲绳县  1945年5月
山姆大叔最温柔
Uncle Sam is mild
像孩子一般温顺
He's peaceful as a child
好莱坞  闭嘴
Hollywood, shut up.
行了  声音小点
Come on, pipe down.
-闭嘴  伙计  -闭嘴
- Shut up, man. - Shut up!
我发誓  好莱坞  我会开枪的
I swear to God, Hollywood, I will shoot you.
闭嘴了行吗
Put a sock in it, will you?
省点力气放战场上
Save the crowing for when we get there.
扫兴的来了
Killjoy was here.
让让路
Give him room.
让开  让开  靠边
Clear! Clear! Move aside!
96师...或者说是仅剩的部分吧
The 96th... or what's left of them.
我们就是去顶替他们的
These are the guys we're replacing.
-我觉得不错  -安全
- Seems good to me. - Clear.
-很好  -安全
- As gold. - Clear.
检查完毕  中士
All clear, Sarge!
我是格洛弗上尉
Captain Glover.
曼维中尉  96师
Lieutenant Manville, 96th.
我们被分过来跟着您了  长官
We've been assigned to you, sir.
好的
Okay.
-给他们弄点吃的  -是  长官
- Let's get these men some chow. - Yes, sir.
这位是  霍威尔中士
This is, uh, Sergeant Howell.
-幸会  长官  -坐
- Good to meet you, sir. - Sit down.
多斯是哪位
Who's Doss?
那边那个
Over there.
你就是多斯
You Doss?
我是埃夫·谢克特
Irv Schecter.
你  我  还有这位佩吉
You, and me and Page here are
就是这里仅剩的军医了
about the only medics we got left in this area.
看来今后我们就要合作了
So, I guess we're gonna be working together.
你刚从前线下来吗
You just come off the line?
那里什么样
What's it like?
我问你那里什么样
I said, What's it like?
钢锯岭
Hacksaw.
我们爬上去六次  被他们赶下来六次
We climbed up six times. Six times, they threw us off.
最后一次  96师几乎已经全军覆没
Last time, there wasn't anything left of the 96th.
他们是野兽
They're animals.
肮脏的野兽
Stinking animals.
日本鬼子不在乎生死
Nips don't care if they live or die.
他们根本就是求死  毫不退缩
They want to die. They keep coming at you.
而且决不放弃
And they ain't never going to give up.
绝不
Never.
来  伙计
Here. Hey, buddy.
日本人会故意以伤员为目标
The Japs deliberately target the wounded.
把你的红十字标志都去掉
Lose all your Red Cross markings.
日本鬼子优先瞄军医
Nips put a premium on shooting medics.
白袖章等于标靶
The white is a bull's-eye.
给你  新头盔
Here, I got you a new helmet.
均码的
One size fits all.
那里就是目标  钢锯岭
That's our objective. Hacksaw Ridge.
占领它  也许就能攻占冲绳
We take it, maybe we get Okinawa.
占领冲绳  就能拿下日本
We get Okinawa, we take Japan.
稍事休息  我们的海军兄弟
Take a breather. Our pals
要帮我们给他们个下马威
in the Navy are going to soften them up for us.
那种炮火下无人能生还
Nobody can survive that shit.
但日本人可以
Oh, but they can.
中尉  这几个碉堡的位置准确吗
Lieutenant, these bunkers here, here and here, is that accurate?
对  有三个...
Yeah, there's three...
准  长官  也许再后点  但...
Yes, sir, maybe a little further back, but it's all...
但上去了就完全不一样了
It's all different up there.
安全  上尉
All clear, Captain.
先生们  出发
Gents, move out.
是血
It's blood.
没错
No shit.
我们不在堪萨斯了  小可爱
We're not in Kansas anymore, Dorothy.
继续爬
Keep climbing.
来  加油
Here, come on.
借过  让让  让开
Coming through, make way. Out of the way.
-布朗  -怎么了
- Brown. - What?
这个给杰索普
Give this to Jessop.
下士
Corporal!
敌袭
Incoming!
趴下
Get down!
他们到底在哪  什么也看不见
Where the hell are they? I can't see nothing.
-问住我了  伙计  -到底在...
- Beats me, pal. - Where the...
军医
Medic!
我们在这边
We're over here!
把手放这里  用手按住  杰克
Put your hand right here. Put your hand on there, Jack.
走  我们走
Come on, come on.
走  我们
Come on, we're going to
会照顾好你的  走  跟我走
get you under cover. Come on, come with me.
我们走  杰克
Come with me, Jack.
继续前进  前进
Keep moving forward! Move!
什么也看不见
I can't see anything.
-是那个吗  -不知道  开枪就是
- Is that one? - I don't know. Just shoot!
好了  我们上
All right, let's go.
维多
Vito!
该死
Oh, shit.
-军医  维多受伤了  -我来了
- Medic! Vito's down! - I'm coming!
好了  我来了
Okay. I'm here.
躲开
Get out of the way!
受伤了吗
You hurt?
没事
I'm fine.
好了  有我呢  拉尔夫  呼吸
Come on, I got you, Ralph. Just breathe.
保持呼吸  呼吸  拉尔夫  没事了
Just breathe. Just breathe, Ralph. It's okay. It's okay.
呼吸  拉尔夫  保持呼吸
Just breathe, Ralph, just breathe.
有我呢  我带你走  走
I got you, I got you. I got you. Come on.
给他一针吗啡  赶紧走了
Give him a shot of morphine and move on.
他撑不过一天的
He's not going to last a day.
求你求你  多斯  别丢下我
Please. Please, Doss, no. No. Don't leave me.
别丢下我  神啊  别丢下我
Don't leave me. God, please don't leave me.
我还有孩子
I've got kids!
求你了求你  别丢下我
Please. Please, don't. Please, don't leave me.
我不会走的  我会带你回家
I ain't going anywhere. I'm going to get you home.
有我呢  拉尔夫  我带你回家
I got you, Ralph. Okay? I'm going to get you home.
这是吗啡  我给你打吗啡
Here comes the morphine. Here comes the morphine.
很快就不痛了  Ralph
It's going to kick in real quick, Ralph.
我们送你走
We're going to get you shifted.
担架  担架
Stretcher! Stretcher!
-起来继续走  小子  -不行  我受伤了
- Get up. Keep moving, son. - I can't, I'm wounded.
你一点事都没有
There's nothing wrong with you.
该死  坚持住  小子
Shit! Hang on, kid.
前进  不动才真的会没命
Move. A sitting duck's a dead one.
前进  冲冲冲
Move. Go, go, go!
优先治疗他
This guy's a priority.
交给我们了  交给我们  这边
We got him, we got him. Here.
优先  你没听过伤员分类吗
A priority? You ever heard of triage?
不等我们送他下去他就会死
He'll be dead before we get him down.
你可说不准
You don't know that!
送他下去  好吗
Get him down. All right?
-好  好  去吧  -好的好的
- Okay. Okay. Go. - Okay. Okay.
没事了  兄弟  我们会送你回家
It's all right, buddy. We're going to get you home.
军医  救我  救我
Medic! Help! Help.
我们看不到他们  那他们也看不到我们
I figure if we can't see them, then they can't see us neither.
救我
Help!
有我呢  弗兰克  哪里受伤了
I got you, Frank. Where you hit?
-看来他们能看到  白痴  -多斯  快走
- I think they can see us, smart ass! - Doss, come on, come on.
帮我一把
Give me a hand here.
趴低点  长官
Get down, sir.
在那边  堡垒
Over there! The bunkers.
我看到他们了  趴低点  长官
I see them. Better stay down, sir.
-发现了  正前方  -我也看到了
- I got 'em, dead ahead. - Yeah, I see 'em, too.
尽量推进  开足火力
Push in as close as you can. Give them everything you've got.
我派特种武器部队两翼夹击
I'll send in the weapons team to flank them.
伤口压紧  你不会有事的  好吗
You keep that tight, you're going to be right as rain. All right?
交给我了  多斯  交给我
I got him, Doss. I got him.
给你  好了  坐在这边
Here you go, come on now. Come sit over here.
嘿
Hey.
你还行吗
You doing okay?
还行
Okay.
开火
And, fire!
趴下
Down!
该死
Son of a bitch.
-你上  -是  长官
- You, get on it. - Yes, sir!
拿着  开火
Take 'em. Go. Fire!
掩护
Cover!
上上上  食尸鬼  进沙坑趴着
Go, go. Go, Ghoul. Get in the hole. Stay there.
上上上史密提  我们掩护你  交替前进
Go! Go, Smitty, we'll cover you. Leapfrog.
掩护
Cover.
炸药包
Satchel!
-食尸鬼  -安全
- Ghoul! - Clear.
加油  扔进去  扔进去  食尸鬼
Come on, stick it. Stick it, Ghoul.
掩护  掩护
Cover! Cover!
该死的
Son of a bitch.
掩护他
Cover his ass.
军医  军医  救救我
Medic! Medic! Help me.
冲
Go!
军医
Medic!
我在  把手压在这里  手压紧
I'm here. Put your hand on it. Put your hand on it!
冲啊
Go, go, go!
食尸鬼  食尸鬼
Ghoul. Ghoul.
你没事  伤哪了
You're okay. Where you hit?
头上撞了个包  没事
You got a bump on the head, that's okay.
你叫什么
What's your name?
-安迪  -安迪什么
- Andy. - Andy what?
安迪·沃克
Andy Walker.
外号呢
Also known as?
食尸鬼
Ghoul.
食尸鬼  食尸鬼  你没事
Ghoul. Ghoul, you're okay, you're okay.
干得好  伙计们  干得好
Good job, men. Good work.
找地方休息  守住这里
Dig in for the night. We hold this spot,
明天扫荡整个山岭
we mop up the rest of the ridge tomorrow.
好了伙计们  在战壕附近找地方睡
Okay, boys. Find yourself a nice safe hole in or near the bunker.
每两小时换班守夜
Rotate watch every two hours.
外面情况不清楚  脑袋趴低给我躲好了
We don't know what's out there. Heads down, asses lower.
不会英语的一律消灭
And shoot anything that don't speak English.
-格里斯也算吗  中士  -第一个就是他
- Does that include Grease, Sarge? - Particularly him.
不管你们是要大小便还是干什么
I don't care if you need to take a piss or a dump,
一个人出去太危险
it ain't safe to go out there alone.
这边  快
Over here, now!
你这是要去哪  多斯
Where the hell are you going, Doss?
外面还有伤员呢  中士
Still more wounded out there, Sarge.
我跟他一起
I'll go with him.
放聪明点  脑袋放低
Be smart. Keep your ears down.
好了  找个地方吧
All right, let's find a spot.
雷纳利和亨利
Rinnelli and Henry dead
没到15分钟就死了  那么直接
in the first 15 minutes, just straight off.
直接死了
Straight off.
彼得森  普派  斯坦福还有墨菲
Peterson, Popeye. Standford and Murphy.
还有佩吉和昂格尔
Page and Unger.
拉斯顿
Ralston.
"和平年代  孩子为父母送终
"In peace, sons bury their fathers,
战争年代  白发人却要送黑发人"
in war, fathers bury their sons."
能不说丧气话了吗
You wanna stop spouting that crap, huh?
一点用没有
It don't help none.
是啊  这句真没错  在这儿说是没用
Yeah, you got that right. Not here.
给我
Hey, give me that.
这个腹部受伤
Hey, we've got an abdominal wound.
他需要输血
This man is going to need some plasma.
-好的  -交给我们吧
- You got it. - Leave him with us.
好的  没事了  有他们呢
Okay. You're okay now. They got you.
我们找个沙坑睡吧
Should we find a hole and dig in?
我看行
Sounds good to me.
头盔戴上
Put your helmet on.
你不吃吗
You ain't going to eat them?
我不吃肉  你自己吃吧
I don't eat meat. Help yourself.
就该想到你不吃肉
Of course you don't.
你女朋友真漂亮
That's one heck of a dame.
你知道你根本
You know you're fighting
配不上人家的  对吧
out of your weight class with her, don't you?
我知道
Yes, I do.
这话不能告诉她
Don't tell her that.
她跟我这样的人在一起才会更幸福
She'd be much happier with a man like me anyway.
是啊  直到她真正了解你
Yeah, until she got to know you.
有时候我真的挺混蛋
I'm an asshole sometimes.
只是有时候吗
Sometimes?
好吧好吧
Yeah, all right. All right.
这些日本人很狡猾
These Japs are sneaky.
第一班我来守  你先睡会儿吧
I'll take first watch, all right? You get some shut-eye.
这梦肯定很可怕
Hell of a dream.
梦到我被烧焦了  什么也做不了
Dreamed I got myself skewered. I couldn't do nothing.
你手边就有枪
Rifle's just there.
枪不咬人的
It won't bite.
会的
Yeah, it will.
看看周围吧
Look around you.
经历了今天这一切
After what we've just been through,
任何没疯的人都会尖叫着要枪了
any sane man would be screaming for a weapon.
我从来没说过我没疯
I never claimed to be sane.
我父亲酗酒
My daddy's a drunk.
他也尝试着戒了几十年  但就是戒不了
He fought it for years, but it kind of got a hold of him hard.
所以他脾气很坏
Made him mean.
至少你还认识你爸
Least you knew him.
有十个人都有可能是我爸
Mine could have been any one of 10 guys,
而且他们没一个是好东西...
and none of them worth a damn, so...
所以是你母亲把你养大的吗
So, your momma raised you?
我知道她是谁  但五岁时她就送我去了孤儿院
I knew her, but she gave me to an orphanage when I was five.
后来再没见过她
Never saw her again.
很快我就学会了仇恨
I learned how to hate quick.
也学会了怎么快速判断人  但我看错了你
I learned how to judge people quicker, and I got you very wrong.
我爸以前经常打我和我哥
My daddy used to beat me
就因为太阳照常升起了
and my brother just because the sun rose,
然后因为太阳落山了又会抽我们
and then whip us just because it set.
这我可以忍受
I could take that...
但当他打算那样对我们的母亲...
...but when he would do it to our momma...
给我滚  你这个臭女人
Get away from me, woman!
够了  别再这样了  你听见了吗
That's enough. No more. Do you hear me?
你开枪啊
Pull the damn trigger.
别  别开枪
Stop it! Stop!
但你并没杀他
But you didn't kill him?
在心里我已经开枪了
In my heart, I did.
所以我向上帝承诺
So that's why I made my promise to God,
我再也不会碰枪
I ain't never going to touch a gun again.
我可不会把我的枪给你  你是个疯子
Well, I ain't giving you mine, 'cause you're crazy.
妈了个...
Son of a...
妈了个逼
Son of a bitch.
撤  快撤  赶紧过来
Move, move! Get your asses over here.
快走
Let's go!
退后  退后  快
Fall back, fall back! Go!
他们是从地道里上来的
They're coming from underground.
探照灯  这里是六号面包师
Searchlight, this is Baker Six.
请求紧急支援
Request immediate support.
目标为YT515
Target is Yoke-Tare-Five-One-Five.
是的  我知道我们在哪
Yes! Yes, I know that's where the hell we are,
但我们顶不了多久了
but I don't expect to be here much longer!
我已经请求了炮击支援
I called an artillery strike.
撤退  快  快撤
Fall back. Move. Move!
撤退  快过来
Fall back! Incoming!
兄弟  有我在  我在
Hey, buddy. I'm right here. Right here.
好了
Okay.
掩护我
Cover me.
撤  撤
Go, go!
快离开这儿  小子
Get out of here, kid!
过来  小子
Come here, son.
你知道怎么做  压住了
You know what to do. Keep pressure on it.
不  我不需要血浆  给他吧
No! Don't need plasma. Give it to him.
那边  我会没事的  快去
Over there. I'll be okay. Go. Go.
-格里斯  -怎么了
Grease!  - What?
把埃夫送回去
Get Irv's back.
-好的  没问题  -回去见
- You got it, okay. - See you soon.
来  我们走
Come on. Come on.
我们必须马上走  来  上来
We gotta move right now. Come on, come on.
撤  撤  快撤
Go! Go! Go!
弹药
Change!
他们人太多  我们赶紧撤
There's too many, get the hell out of here!
撤  撤退
Move! Move!
我很害怕  我害怕
I'm scared. I'm scared.
这能帮你缓解疼痛
It's going to help the pain.
别  不  你不准死  坚持
No, don't. Don't you do that. Come on.
坚持住  史密提  保持清醒
Come on, Smitty, you stay with me.
走  我们得走了
Let's go. We gotta move.
帮我把他放下去  帮我把他放下去
Help me get him down. Help me get him down.
好的
Yeah.
快  我们快走  快
Come on, let's move. Come on.
无能为力了  兄弟  他已经死了
Can't help him, buddy, he's gone.
-不  -快  我们得离开这里
- No. - Come on! We gotta get outta here!
快走
Let's go!
快  走了
Come on, let's go.
大家快撤
Come on. Everyone.
快爬下去
Off the ridge!
你想要我怎么做
What is it you want of me?
我不明白
I don't understand.
我听不到你的声音
I can't hear you.
医疗兵  救我  救救我
Medic, help me! Help me!
救救我
Help me!
主啊  快救救我
Help me, Lord.
好吧
All right.
会有人照顾好你  慢点  慢点
You're in good hands. Easy does it. Easy.
六...  七...
six... eight...
十四
Fourteen.
马上把这些人送到安全的地方
Get these men secured immediately.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
二等兵福特  还剩多少人
Private Ford, how many?
只下来三十二个  长官
Thirty-two only came down, sir.
-天  -开车
- Good Lord. - Let's go!
-把他们抬上车  -是  长官
- Let's load 'em up. - Yes, sir.
哈利  我是戴斯蒙德
Harry. It's Desmond.
我会治好你的  保持呼吸  好吗
We going to fix you up. You just got to keep breathing. Okay?
-上校要见你  长官  -吉普车给我
- Colonel wants to see you, sir. - I need your jeep.
你们两个守在这盯着  看有没有日本人
You two stay here, keep watch, keep your eyes peeled for Japs.
-但是  -守在这儿盯着
- No, but... - Stay here! Keep watch.
-是  长官  -是  长官
- Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
救我  救救我
Help. Help me.
小心  有我在
Watch out. I got you.
把手放上面  一直压着
Put your hand on it. Keep pressure on it.
-我会回来救你的  好吗  -好的
- I'm comin' back. Okay? - Okay.
慢点  小伙子们  慢点
Easy, fellas, easy.
接住
Here we go.
好了  伙计们  我数三下
Okay, guys, let's go. On the count of three.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
医疗兵  这里需要帮助
Help, medic over here!
没事的  兄弟  振作点
It's okay, buddy, hold it together.
我们到山崖边上了  埃里克
We're at the edge, Eric.
坐稳了  好吗
You just sit tight, okay?
你会没事的  埃里克
You're okay, Eric.
会没事的  兄弟
You're okay, buddy.
妈的  这样一定行
Son of a gun, this is going to work.
一边套一条腿  埃里克
One for each leg, Eric.
马上给你穿好就送你下去
We're going to get you dressed up in a jiffy and get you down.
有我在
I got you.
有我在  埃里克
I got you now, Eric.
你要信任我  埃里克  你必须信任我
You have to trust me now, Eric. You're gonna have to trust me.
日本人
Japs!
别开枪  是自己人
Hold on, one of ours.
别开枪  快过去  快
Hold on! Let's go, let's go!
有我在  有我在  有我在
I got you. I got you. I got you.
加油  有我在
Come on, I got you.
你会没事的  会没事的
You're okay. You're okay.
汉克  又下来一个
Hank, another one.
上校  停止对钢锯岭的炮火攻击
Colonel, call off the artillery attack on Hacksaw.
联系不上他们  还有一百多人没有撤离
Couldn't call it in. There's still over 100 men left up there.
让他们停止对钢锯岭的炮火攻击
Tell them to call off the artillery on Hacksaw.
坐下说  杰克  我给你倒杯水
Sit down, Jack. I'll get you a drink.
我们失去了掩护
We just lost our cover.
日本人在搜查  我们得赶紧撤了  快
They're stirring, we got to move. Come on.
来得正是时候  他们不断从...
About time. They just keep coming by the...
行了  行了  快把他抬起来
OK, OK. Pick it up.
我抬这边
I got this.
多斯  多斯
Doss. Doss.
救  救我
Help. Help me.
你要相信我  深吸一口气
You're gonna have to trust me. Take a breath.
我们走  兄弟  我们走
Let's go, buddy. Let's go.
杰克
Jack,
你无法确认你在上面的人的人是死是活
you don't know if your men up there are dead or alive.
你不能在没有支援的情况下再上去
You can't go back up there without reinforcements.
这样会把剩下的人都害死的
You'll end up killing the rest of them.
那就给我支援
Then give me the reinforcements.
我没有新兵了  好吗  我没有部队了
I don't have any fresh men, okay? I don't have any troops.
今天三个部队都牺牲了
Three battalions got wiped out today.
援兵可不是一天就能到的
It'll take more than a day to get men in here.
我等不了那么久
I need them faster than that.
没事的  没事的
It's okay, it's okay.
没事  没事
It's all right. It's all right.
一切都会没事的
Everything's okay.
吗啡  对你有好处
Morphine. It's good.
皮尼克  我是多斯
Pinnick, Pinnick. Pinnick. It's Doss.
我是多斯  别出声  有我在
It's Doss. Be quiet. Be quiet. I got you.
-你中弹了吗  -是的  我看不见了
- Are you hit? - Yeah. I can't see.
安静  安静点
Be quiet. Just be quiet.
先别动  有我在  别动
Hold still now. I got you. Hold tight.
好了  现在呢
There you go. Try now. Try now.
我还以为我瞎了
I thought I was blind!
小点声  你能走路吗
Shh... Keep it down. Can you walk?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们赶紧离开这儿  好吗  来
We got to get out of here, okay? Come on.
好了  我们接住你了
Good. Okay, we got you.
接住你了
We got you.
特德
Hey, Ted.
是我  戴斯蒙德  我会治好你的
It's me, it's Desmond. I'm gonna fix you up.
-准备好离开这里了吗  -当然
- You ready to get out of here? - Sure am.
拜托  主啊  帮我再多救一个
Please, Lord, help me get one more.
帮我再多救一个
Help me get one more.
Please, help me get one more.
再多一个  帮我再多救一个
One more. Help me get one more.
再多一个   帮我再多救一个
再多一个
One more.
让一下
Coming through.
这些人都是从哪儿来的
Where the hell are these guys coming from?
从钢锯岭上
From Hacksaw.
-我以为他们都撤离了  -没全撤离
- I thought they pulled out. - Not all of them.
有个傻瓜一直在上面吊伤员下来
Some nut's up there dragging wounded from the top.
甚至还送下来几个日本人
Even lowered a couple of Japs.
不过他们没活下来  都直接送到你这了
They didn't make it. Back with you directly.
慢点  慢点  好了  走吧
Easy, easy. All set, move out.
快过来  现在到处是日本人
Get in here. There's Nips everywhere.
你小子可以啊  玉米杆二等兵
Son of a bitch. Private Corn Stalk.
你还真是让人充满惊喜
You are nothing if not full of surprises.
你需要吗啡吗
You want some morphine?
这还用说  要么吗啡要么一枪崩了我
Hell, yes. That or a bullet.
这就给你
Okay.
好了
There. There you go.
好了  让我看看
All right, let me see. Let me see.
这怎么样  好吧  没那么严重
How's this doing? Okay, not bad.
我看看
Let me see.
没有看起来那么糟糕
It looks much worse than it is.
肯定还有姑娘愿意吻你
Girls will still want to kiss you.
中士  你能在这儿等一会儿吗
Sarge, you okay here for a while?
可以  快带他走
Yeah, fine. Get out of here.
我会马上回来的
I'm coming back.
准备好了吗  我们走  你和我  快
You ready? Let's go. You and me, come on.
上尉  你得来看看这个
Captain. There's something you gotta see.
我们的人一整晚都在陆陆续续被送下来
Our guys have been coming down in droves all night.
然后好莱坞也被送来了
And Hollywood's here.
我还以为再也见不到那家伙了
I never thought I'd see that guy again.
跟我来  他就在这儿
Come on, follow me. He's right here.
这是什么情况
What the hell is this?
你怎么样  先生
How you doing, sir?
嘿  上尉
Hey, Cap.
上尉
Captain.
-能再见到你真是太好了  -格洛弗上尉
- It's good to see you, kid. - Captain Glover, sir.
你怎么下来的
How'd you get down, son?
是多斯  他现在还在上面
Doss. Howell's still up there.
什么  霍威尔和多斯救的你们吗
What, Howell and Doss did this?
基本只有多斯
Mostly just Doss.
-只有多斯  -只有多斯
- Just Doss? - Just Doss.
是啊  多斯  那个懦夫
Yeah, Doss, the coward.
你还真是块狗皮膏药啊  是吧
You're like gum on a shoe, ain't you?
把枪给我
Give me this.
你不觉得现在开始瞄准训练有点晚了吗
It's a bit late for target practice now, don't you think?
-跳上来  -你开玩笑呢吧
- Jump on it. - You're kidding.
没开玩笑  我拖着你走
No, I'm going to drag you.
来吧
Let's do it.
-准备好了吗  -好了
- Ready? - Yeah.
我们走
Let's go.
敌人来了
We got company.
快
Come on.
把手举起来
Arms up.
你逗我呢  玉米杆
You gotta be kidding me, Corn Stalk.
"我是让你们打单套结
"You're tying a bowline, boy,
不是做胸罩"
not building a bra."
来
Come on.
-准备好了吗  -嗯
- Ready? - Uh-huh.
走
Get on.
-放我下来  -是  中士
- Put me down! - Yes, Sarge.
-霍威尔中士  -多斯还在上面
- Sergeant Howell. - Doss is still up there.
-什么情况  -日本人在追他
- What the hell? - He's got Japs on his tail.
接住他了
We got him.
好了  好了
That's good. That's good.
好了  接住他了
It's okay, we got him.
-没事了  多斯  -好了  多斯
- It's okay, Doss. - Come on, Doss, come on.
-你安全了  -好了  多斯
- You're safe. - Come on, Doss.
戴斯蒙德  没事了  没事了
Desmond, it's all right, it's all right.
戴斯蒙德
Desmond.
慢点  撑住
Easy, easy. Here, come on.
你受伤了吗
Are you wounded?
没有  没有
No. No.
我们快把这位士兵送去医疗营  快
Let's get this soldier to a hospital tent, right now.
-来  慢点  -慢点
- Come on, easy now. - Easy, easy.
让一让
Make some space.
这里需要人来清理一下
We need someone to come and clean up in here.
埃夫在哪儿
Where's Irv?
-埃夫  你是说医疗那个兵谢克特  -对
- Irv? You mean, Schecter the medic? - Yeah.
他没撑住  死于休克  没有血浆了
He didn't make it. He died of shock. No plasma.
抱歉
Sorry.
过去我只看到个消瘦的孩子
All I saw was a skinny kid.
并不了解你是怎样的人
I didn't know who you were.
在报效国家这件事上
You've done more than any other man could have done
你比任何人做得都多
in the service of his country.
我之前对你的看法实在是大错特错
And I have never been more wrong about someone in my life.
我希望你有一天能够原谅我
I hope one day you can forgive me.
我们明天就要回去战斗
We have to go back up tomorrow.
我知道明天是你做祷告的日子
I realize that tomorrow is your Sabbath.
这里的大部分人都不像你那样有信仰
Most of these men don't believe the same way you do.
但是他们都相信你对自己的信仰有多坚定
But they believe so much in how much you believe.
你在那山脊上做的事  真可谓是奇迹
And what you did on that ridge, it's nothing short of a miracle,
他们也想被神迹福泽
and they want a piece of it.
只有你在他们才愿意上去奋战
And they're not going to go up there without you.
你们在拖延什么呢  上尉
What the hell is your delay, Captain?
十分钟前就该进行攻击了
You were supposed to begin that assault 10 minutes ago!
-我们在等  长官  -等什么
- We're waiting, sir. - Waiting for what?
等二等兵多斯为我们祈祷完毕  长官
For Private Doss to finish praying for us, sir.
二等兵多斯在为你们祈祷
Private Doss is praying for you?
这个二等兵多斯是什么人
Who the hell is Private Doss?
开始行动吧
Let's go to work.
趴下  趴下
Down. Get down!
趴在地上  趴地上  马上
Get on the ground. On the ground. Now!
躺下  躺下  我给你注射吗啡
Lay down, lay down. I got the morphine.
快走  把这些人带出去
Let's go, let's get these men out of here.
我的圣经  圣经  圣经
My Bible... My Bible. My Bible...
停  停停停  停
Stop. Stop, stop, stop. Stop!
我的圣经  圣经  圣经
My Bible, my Bible, my Bible.
好
Okay.
你要回家了  戴斯蒙德
You're going home, Desmond.
我们把钢锯岭拿下了
We've taken Hacksaw.
等下  等下  戴斯蒙德
Hold up, hold up! Desmond!
戴斯蒙德
Desmond.
戴斯蒙德·多斯在钢锯岭共救下七十五名伤兵
他是第一个拒服兵役但却获得荣誉勋章的士兵
这是美国战争的最高奖励
戴斯蒙德和多萝西结婚  相伴到1991年多萝西去世
他对自己的英雄事迹非常谦虚
并认为这都是上帝的指引
我那时候一直在祈祷
I was praying the whole time.
一直在祈祷
I just kept praying,
戴斯蒙德·多斯 - 2003
"主啊  请帮我再多救一个"
"Lord, please help me get one more."
当我又救了一个  我会说
When I got this, I said,
"主啊  请帮我再多救一个"
"Lord, please help me get one more."
他说"真正的英雄都被葬在这里了"
我想任何人都不该
I would say anyone is wrong
试图动摇他人的信仰
to try to compromise somebody's conviction.
哈尔·多斯
无论是在军队还是哪里
I don't care whether it's army or what it is.
当你心存信念  那可不是玩笑
When you own a conviction, that is not a joke.
那代表了你是怎样的人
That's what you are.
格洛弗上尉
尽管为了让他拿起枪
Even though I said those things to him
我对他说了那些话
in regard to carrying a rifle,
如果他不拿枪
then he would never be by
我永远不会与他并肩作战
my damn side at all unless he had a rifle.
但最终
But then, in the long run,
原来他才是活着的最勇敢的人之一
finding out that he was one of the bravest persons alive.
而且最终他救了我的命
And then to have him end up saving my life
真是整件事中最讽刺的一点
was the irony of the whole thing.
那个伙计的脸和眼睛上都是血
Blood had run down into the fella's face and eyes.
他躺在那里呻吟  向医疗兵求救
He was laying there just groaning and calling for a medic.
我从水壶里倒了些水
I took water from my canteen,
又拿了些绷带  帮他洗了脸
got some bandage, and I washed his face.
清洗过后  他的眼睛逐渐睁开
And when I... was washing his eyes, his eyes came open.
天  他一下就有精神了
Man, he just lit up.
他说  "我还以为我瞎了"
He says, "I thought I was blind."
他的笑容是我在这场战争中
And if I hadn't got anything more out of the war
得到的最好回报  我很满足了
than that smile he gave me, I'd have been well repaid.
戴斯蒙德·多斯于2006年3月逝世
享年87岁